<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>🪴nicothyun e-garden</title>
      <link>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on 🪴nicothyun e-garden</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>Go as a River</title>
    <link>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/books/go-as-a-river</link>
    <guid>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/books/go-as-a-river</guid>
    <description>Notes #natural-history#historical-fiction four corners monument ”Man flooded the town of Iola; now nature is bringing back its ghost” by The Los Angeles Times racism &amp; bigotry women’s suffering against bigotry, sacrifices and grief Quotes pg 7: I knew the town of Iola when it woke each morning to fragrant breakfasts and bustling farms and ranches, how the sunrise illuminated the east side of Main then inched uptown, across the train tracks and schoolyard, to ignite the tiny church&#039;s one round red and blue stained glass window.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>The Tales of Genji</title>
    <link>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/books/tales-of-genji</link>
    <guid>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/books/tales-of-genji</guid>
    <description>date: 13-09-2023, nlb seminar by professor deborah shamoon. social context tales of genji - Murasaki (purple) 💜 shikibu (not real name) written in late 9th to early 10th century not a religious text unlike literature of it’s time period, it was written for entertainment because compared to most of the classics, tales of genji had less warfare, more romance.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>why and hows of note taking</title>
    <link>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/notetaking-process</link>
    <guid>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/notetaking-process</guid>
    <description>note taking process and rituals zettelkasten way - organic and flat so there’s less pressure to take notes notion as get things done!! system while obsidian is intended for digital gardening and acts as my PKM random capture-away thoughts organic learning process? evergreen notes by andy matuschak as notes and ideas progress and evolves from 🍃 Leaf, to 🌿 Branch and then 🌲 Tree.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 14:19:13 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>my tiny internet</title>
    <link>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/</link>
    <guid>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/</guid>
    <description>Hello internet wanderer, you have stumbled to my public garden of thought. This abode is messy, chaotic and probably would not make much sense to a stranger but it is where I explore, prune and gather my curiosities into an interconnected map.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 14:19:13 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>clean(er) energy</title>
    <link>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/clean(er)-energy</link>
    <guid>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/clean(er)-energy</guid>
    <description>producing and processing bits and bytes (in the digital world) still requires atoms (in the physical world). more technology means generating and consuming more energy.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 14:19:13 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>battery energy</title>
    <link>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/battery-energy</link>
    <guid>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/battery-energy</guid>
    <description>battery energies are moving from lithium-ion to solid-state batteries, they are a form of new energy away from fossil fuels, clean(er) energy different batteries technologies: solid-state batteries (i.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 14:19:12 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Rokuon-ji Temple, Kyoto</title>
    <link>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/places/Rokuon-ji-Temple,-Kyoto</link>
    <guid>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/places/Rokuon-ji-Temple,-Kyoto</guid>
    <description> renamed rokuon-ji but eventually became known as kinkaku-ji 1894: temple was opened to public to help it financially in 1894 in 1950, temple was burnt down by a young monk, hayashi yoken.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 14:19:12 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Lombok, Indonesia</title>
    <link>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/places/Lombok,-Indonesia</link>
    <guid>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/places/Lombok,-Indonesia</guid>
    <description>lombok strait: south of lombok, near kuta places to go/went **&amp; experienced mana yoga, ashtanga yoga sore full moon soundbath yoga bat cave, mawan beach mt rinjani trekking lanne beach / pantai selong belanak for beginner surfing secret gilis tour - gilli naggu, gilii kedis and gili sudak at south-west lombok (!!! very beautiful beaches and cerulean blue waters) loose observations tourism as main income.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 14:19:12 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>hiroshima museum of art observations</title>
    <link>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/places/Hiroshima-Museum-of-Art</link>
    <guid>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/places/Hiroshima-Museum-of-Art</guid>
    <description>3rd august 2023 nihon ga 日本画 - genre by a traditional technique from the start of the Meiji era (India ink and colours over paper and silk) v.s. to yo-ga (japanese western style) (oil paintings over canvas) some interesting pieces: Yasuda yukihiko (1884-1978) 一茶 seiichi horiuchi - children book illustrations.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 14:19:12 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Fukuoka Art Museum</title>
    <link>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/places/Fukuoka-Art-Museum</link>
    <guid>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/places/Fukuoka-Art-Museum</guid>
    <description>8 august 2023 Louis Joseph collin at the seaside 1892 mentor of kuroda seiki and okada saburosuke who laid foundation of japanese modern art jean michael basquiat 1984 untitled snapshot of new York city where basquat grew up azechi umetaro interest in animals, plants and people’s lives in the mountains, rather than the harshness of nature shimokawa tochiro 1958 farm village depict harsh realities of farm life zao wou ki still two of us 1974 oil on canvas studied in Paris, zao created abstract paintings on theme of nature and landscapes which are described as fusion of western and eastern aesthetics mark rothko untitled 1961 plunge daily life into the sublime of his artwork uses violet and brown and cream egami keita psychedelic batoquism no 7 combined origami paper to combine in bright colours and geometric shapes.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 14:19:12 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>