<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>🪴nicothyun e-garden</title>
      <link>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on 🪴nicothyun e-garden</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>Go as a River</title>
    <link>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/books/Go-as-a-River</link>
    <guid>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/books/Go-as-a-River</guid>
    <description>Notes four corners monument ”Man flooded the town of Iola; now nature is bringing back its ghost” by The Los Angeles Times racism &amp; bigotry women’s suffering against bigotry, sacrifices and grief Quotes pg 7: I knew the town of Iola when it woke each morning to fragrant breakfasts and bustling farms and ranches, how the sunrise illuminated the east side of Main then inched uptown, across the train tracks and schoolyard, to ignite the tiny church&#039;s one round red and blue stained glass window.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>The Tales of Genji</title>
    <link>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/books/The-Tales-of-Genji</link>
    <guid>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/books/The-Tales-of-Genji</guid>
    <description>date: 13-09-2023, nlb seminar by professor deborah shamoon. social context tales of genji - Murasaki (purple) 💜 shikibu (not real name) written in late 9th to early 10th century not a religious text unlike literature of it’s time period, it was written for entertainment because compared to most of the classics, tales of genji had less warfare, more romance.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Example</title>
    <link>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/blockchain/runes</link>
    <guid>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/blockchain/runes</guid>
    <description> Runes are fungible tokens issued directly on Bitcoin using the Runes protocol. Proposed by Casey Rodarmor (creator of Ordinals) Doesn’t require off-chain data or a native token to operate Bitcoin Runes’ onchain data storage is in the OP_RETURN part of a transaction.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 13:52:22 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Example</title>
    <link>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/blockchain/bitcoin-defi</link>
    <guid>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/blockchain/bitcoin-defi</guid>
    <description> Use of smart contracts to Bitcoin in order to unlock Bitcoin DeFi. However, bitcoin faces the blockchain trilemma challenges. Bitcoin’s issue = composability and it’s limited scripting language L1 like Stacks is unleashing Bitcoin through Clarity (a new programming language for Bitcoin) Bitcoin’s security is high but it comes at the cost of programmability Bitcoin ordinals seen as a first breakthrough for Bitcoin application tier and could help move narrative from a pure “store of value” to something more utilitarian.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 13:52:22 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>lombok, indonesia</title>
    <link>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/places/lombok,-indonesia</link>
    <guid>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/places/lombok,-indonesia</guid>
    <description>lombok strait: south of lombok, near kuta places to go/went **&amp; experienced mana yoga, ashtanga yoga sore full moon soundbath yoga bat cave, mawan beach mt rinjani trekking lanne beach / pantai selong belanak for beginner surfing secret gilis tour - gilli naggu, gilii kedis and gili sudak at south-west lombok (!!! very beautiful beaches and cerulean blue waters) loose observations tourism as main income.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 11:35:17 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>hiroshima museum of art observations</title>
    <link>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/places/hiroshima-museum-of-art</link>
    <guid>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/places/hiroshima-museum-of-art</guid>
    <description>3rd august 2023 nihon ga 日本画 - genre by a traditional technique from the start of the Meiji era (India ink and colours over paper and silk) v.s. to yo-ga (japanese western style) (oil paintings over canvas) some interesting pieces: Yasuda yukihiko (1884-1978) 一茶 seiichi horiuchi - children book illustrations.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 11:35:17 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Rokuon-ji Temple, Kyoto</title>
    <link>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/places/Rokuon-ji-Temple,-Kyoto</link>
    <guid>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/places/Rokuon-ji-Temple,-Kyoto</guid>
    <description> renamed rokuon-ji but eventually became known as kinkaku-ji 1894: temple was opened to public to help it financially in 1894 in 1950, temple was burnt down by a young monk, hayashi yoken.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 11:35:17 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>fukuoka art museum</title>
    <link>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/places/fukuoka-art-museum</link>
    <guid>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/places/fukuoka-art-museum</guid>
    <description>8 august 2023 Louis Joseph collin at the seaside 1892 mentor of kuroda seiki and okada saburosuke who laid foundation of japanese modern art jean michael basquiat 1984 untitled snapshot of new York city where basquat grew up azechi umetaro interest in animals, plants and people’s lives in the mountains, rather than the harshness of nature shimokawa tochiro 1958 farm village depict harsh realities of farm life zao wou ki still two of us 1974 oil on canvas studied in Paris, zao created abstract paintings on theme of nature and landscapes which are described as fusion of western and eastern aesthetics mark rothko untitled 1961 plunge daily life into the sublime of his artwork uses violet and brown and cream egami keita psychedelic batoquism no 7 combined origami paper to combine in bright colours and geometric shapes.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 11:35:17 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>women writers</title>
    <link>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/people-(great-minds)/women-writers</link>
    <guid>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/people-(great-minds)/women-writers</guid>
    <description> Sophia Tolstaya Murusaki Shikibu (wrote The Tales of Genji) .</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 11:35:17 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>alfred russell wallace</title>
    <link>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/people-(great-minds)/alfred-russell-wallace</link>
    <guid>https://nicothyun.github.io/garden/people-(great-minds)/alfred-russell-wallace</guid>
    <description> Alfred Russell Wallace was born in 1823, Wales, and died at the age of 90 in 1913. known as for his studies in natural history (naturalist), geographer &amp; socialist.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 11:35:17 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>